<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Potential COVID-19 cases monitoring</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Potential COVID-19 cases monitoring</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 trends by CCG level</title>
      <link>/2020/09/16/covid-19-trends-by-ccg-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/16/covid-19-trends-by-ccg-level/</guid>
      <description>Using the new algorithm ASMODEE (Automatic Selection of Models and Outlier Detection for Epidemics) we monitor changes in potential COVID-19 cases reported through the NHS pathways, including calls to 111, 999, and 111-online. These analyses are broken down by Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCG). Only the last 6 weeks of data are used. The last week of data is not used to define the temporal trend so that recent outliers can be detected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 trends in England</title>
      <link>/2020/09/16/covid-19-trends-in-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/16/covid-19-trends-in-england/</guid>
      <description>Using the new algorithm ASMODEE (Automatic Selection of Models and Outlier Detection for Epidemics) we monitor changes in potential COVID-19 cases reported through the NHS pathways, including calls to 111, 999, and 111-online. Only the last 6 weeks of data are used.
Note: this research has not been peer-reviewed yet. This website is still experimental. Please contact the authors before using its content.
Models considered here for trend fitting include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the data</title>
      <link>/about-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-data/</guid>
      <description>We use the NHS pathways data reporting potential COVID-19 cases in England. These data include all reports classified as &amp;lsquo;potential COVID-19 cases&amp;rsquo; notified via calls to 111, 999, and 111-online systems. These data are not confirmed cases, and are subject to unknown reporting biases. They likely include a substantial fraction of &amp;lsquo;false positives&amp;rsquo; (cases classified as potential COVID-19 which are in fact due to other illness), as well as under-reporting (true COVID-19 cases not reported).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the model</title>
      <link>/about-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-model/</guid>
      <description>The trend analyses presented here use Automatic Selection of Models Outlier DEtection for Epidemics (ASMODEE). This new algorithm has not been peer reviewed yet.
ASMODEE in a nutshell ASMODEE aims to detect recent deviation from the trend followed by the data in time series. Data is first partitioned into &amp;lsquo;recent&amp;rsquo; data, using the last ‘k’ observations as supplementary individuals, and older data used to fit the trend. Trend-fitting is done by fitting a series of user-specified models for the time series, with different methods for selecting best fit (see details, and the argument ‘method’).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>